As the countdown begins for the new millennium there is
still one number you can always count on.
The World Is Not Enough is a adventure, action,
thriller film directed by Michael Apted.
Greed, revenge, world dominance and high-tech terrorism – it's all in a day's work for Bond,
who's on a mission to protect a beautiful oil heiress from a notorious terrorist.
In a race against time that culminates in a dramatic submarine showdown, Bond works to defuse the
international power struggle that has the world's oil supply hanging in the balance.
James Bond, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Elektra, played by Sophie Marceau.
Renard, played by Robert Carlyle.
Christmas Jones, played by Denise Richards.
Valentin Zukovsky, played by Robbie Coltrane.
M, played by Judi Dench.
The World Is Not Enough is a 1999 action spy film, the nineteenth in the James Bond series produced by Eon
Productions and the third to star Pierce Brosnan as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
It was directed by Michael Apted, from an original story and
screenplay by Neal Purvis, Robert Wade, and Bruce Feirstein.
It was produced by Michael G.
Wilson and Barbara Broccoli.
The title is the translation of the motto on the Bond family coat of
arms, first seen in On Her Majesty's Secret Service.
The film's plot revolves around the murder of billionaire businessman Sir Robert King by the terrorist Renard, and Bond's
subsequent assignment to protect King's daughter Elektra, who was previously held for ransom by Renard.
During his assignment, Bond unravels a scheme to increase petroleum prices
by triggering a nuclear meltdown in the waters of Istanbul.
Filming locations included Spain, France, Azerbaijan, Turkey, and
the UK, with interiors shot at Pinewood Studios.
Despite receiving mixed reviews from critics, with the plot and Denise Richards' casting frequently targeted for criticism,
The World Is Not Enough earned over $361 million worldwide, becoming the eighth highest-grossing film of 1999.
It was also the first Eon-produced Bond film officially released by the mainline
Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer label instead of United Artists, the franchise's original owner and distributor.
The World Is Not Enough was followed by Die Another Day in 2002.
The film explores themes of mission, oil, mi6, heiress, bilbao, spain.
The tone is intense.